January 5, Friday
Alarm
School starts today, huh?
What's all in the past? I took it so personally!
God!
Natsume might have realized.
You're gonna be late for your first day of school!
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Okay, okay, I'm coming!
I don't wanna go to school.
I say a goodbye to your memory.
Would you call me crazy?
How are things going over there?
The shy person who sits next to me
Would blush every time I said "Thank you".
Together, we decided on a secret phrase.
Even if we were far apart, I'm sure I'd recognize it immediately.
If we can meet again some new day,
I'll hope this simple letter can reach you.
Ahh, but you don't even bother to read it.
Why'd you just leave it sitting there?
I say a goodbye to your memory.
Your long hair hides your cheeks from view,
So I'm having trouble reading you.
Even though I use to know you better than anyone else.
You're no longer there sitting next to me.
Hey, Happy New Year.
Did you get fat?
I ate a lot of mochi.
Hey, what's that?
What school is that uniform from?
I'm asking you!
Well, I think I also went too far...
Yeah.
Mio!
Morning! Happy New Year! Let's have a good one!
Morning. Happy New Year. Let's have a good one...
What? You like Soma and him?
Huh?! Why?
Oh, am I wrong?
What's with you?
Don't worry about it.
Oh! Sanae!
It's so unfair! Haruto keeps winning!
You're so lame!
What?!
Don't "what" me.
Dammit! I'll show you with the next one!
Oh, Hazuki!
Morning!
Yeah, morning.
Let's head in.
Man, a rare one isn't appearing for me!
I said it'll appear. Right?
It will. You've got real luck, anyway.
Use up all your luck here, you guys!
I'm gonna keep it for my entrance exam.
I'm gonna pass my entrance exam with my abilities.
I don't have any entrance exams.
What?! Then, give me your poop! That's lucky, right?
Does he realize he was rejected?
Yoriko!
It's good that it doesn't bother him, right?
That's true, but...
Later.
Slides is here.
Happy New Year, everyone! Let's keep chugging along
until graduation. Now, be seated.
That's rude, Slides!
Now then, we'll be heading to the opening ceremony
in the gym, so bring your coats, if you're cold.
Once we get back, we're going to have a lottery
for the new seating arrangement.
Well, it's already the third semester
of your third year, but we'll do it anyway.
It'd be fine to just stay in our current seats.
Man, I just go to cram school early,
even though school ends early.
Hey, wanna go somewhere?
I want to, but the National Center Test
is next week! The Center Test!
There's no Right or Left Test...
Sorry, Haruto.
It's okay. I get it.
Must be nice that you found a job,
Haruto. I'm seriously jealous!
Hello!
Hey.
Oh, hey, Soma?
Huh?
The teacher told me you should clear
out your stuff from the club room.
Yeah, okay. I'm gonna stop by the club room.
Okay.
Then, we'll see you tomorrow.
See ya.
Yeah.
Entrance exams are so intense!
Must be nice. The guys that can go
to college have a future ahead of them.
Are you done?
Yeah. Thanks, Mio.
Don't mention it.
Okay, let's go home!
You've got something to give her
before we go, remember?!
Oh, yeah!
Huh?
This is from me and Momoka. Ta-da!
Amulet
What? Did you go out of your way to get that?
We got it when we visited the shrine on New Year's.
Thanks!
I have this for you, too!
Ta-da!
Success
in Love
Why?
Now, now, don't say what you're about to say.
Your smile is kinda scary.
Success
in Love
Amulet
That's not good at all...
Frantically using entrance exams as an excuse.
Momo, what about me?
I don't have one for you.
Why?
I said I don't have one for you.
I asked why.
I don't have one for you, so I've got nothing.
I. Asked. Why.
Mio.
I don't have one for you, so I've got nothing.
Why is that?
Yeah, sorry, I'm gonna go.
I've still got stuff to do.
What? Talking with Slides?
Not that, but it's something like that.
Huh? Huh?
I found your room, Izumi!
Mio was acting kinda weird.
What stuff did she need to do?
Maybe confess her love or something.
No way.
Oh! But...
Soma!
Hm?
Oh, never mind. Bye-bye!
Let's go.
What was that about?
Everything's really over.
"I really do think that I went a bit too far
when I said it didn't involve you..."
"Sorry."
I'll tell him that.
Ah!
You don't have to follow me.
You're gonna stand out if you're seen alone,
wearing that gakuran uniform.
I'm gonna stand out if I'm seen with you.
You won't know what to do if someone starts
a weird rumor or something, huh?
Natsume?
Whatcha doin' there?
No, I'm just—
You're just...?
I don't know...
Why are you running away from Mio?
Did something happen over winter break?
Hm?
Until the
last ball!
Is this Soma's?
Yeah.
That reminds me, was it okay to let Izumi be?
I thought you needed talk to him.
Uh, yeah, I did, but...
Did you fight or something?
Fight? Um, I guess.
Well, Izumi criticized me a bit.
I didn't really want talk about that stuff.
I guess I was a bit too harsh on him.
So, things are awkward?
Something like that.
So, I thought about apologizing, but...
You got jealous since Izumi was flirting with Komiya.
N-No!
I get it, though. It's like that with you guys, too, huh?
Well, we won't be having
conversations on LINE anymore.
Soma's ship sunk, too, after all.
Yoriko!
It's fine. Natsume knows about it.
Yeah, well, for the most part.
I'm home.
Welcome back. How was school?
Hm?
Until the
last ball!
Good luck on your entrance exam. I'm rooting for you!
Yeah, thanks. See ya.
Natsume, hold on!
Huh?
There's something I want to talk to you about.
Haruto, move. I want to vacuum that spot.
I'm trash, Granny.
Maybe you are, if you just sleep all Sunday.
Why don't you go to the sandlot baseball game?
Saeki's boy invited you, didn't he?
I'm not in the mood.
Then, how about hanging out with Junpei?
He's got entrance exams... unlike me.
That boy probably doesn't study anyway.
Saeki
Today
If you've got some time,
come meet the team.
Let's play
ball today
Eita
Today
You free? Wanna hang out somewhere?
I'm sorry for bringing you all the way here with me.
I'm gonna stop by my cram school,
so don't worry about it.
So, you wanted to talk about Soma, right?
Yeah.
Hey.
Which team?
The losing one.
Hello!
Oh, you're here, Soma!
I'm sorry I'm late, Saeki.
I asked you to come all the way out here. Don't sweat it.
Who's that?
Oh, he's my friend.
We used to play ball in middle school,
so I brought him along.
I'm Izumi.
So, you two have experience. We're gonna win today.
Mr. Komada, this is Soma.
He's my junior from high school.
He's gonna come work at our factory in the spring.
I see.
Hm?
Nice. You're huge.
Nice batting, Mr. Shindo!
All right! Keep going, Ishii. The pitcher's strong!
First, let's get a point!
You guys are pretty serious about this.
It wouldn't be fun, if we weren't.
All right! Go, go!
Yeah, I guess...
I see.
So, Soma actually asked you out.
Everyone knew, huh?
Yoriko talked about it the other day.
Sorry. I was the one who suggested
that we leave you and Soma alone together.
It's okay.
Still, that means... you're fine with rejecting him, right?
Yeah.
It was a first for me.
It caught me off guard, so I responded immediately.
But now, I think I probably should've
given it some thought before responding.
Does that mean...
You might answer differently
if you were asked right now?
I think... I'd give him the same answer again.
Oh, but that doesn't mean I hate
or dislike him or anything like that.
Yeah.
It's just that Soma and I hadn't really talked until recently,
and there's so much I don't know about him.
It's much too soon to go out with him right now.
Yeah.
Besides, I won't be in town once we graduate.
I've been thinking about Soma all
the time, ever since that day.
It's kind of embarrassing... talking about this stuff.
Why don't you tell him?
Tell him you want to answer
his question again but properly.
Well...
I think it'd be good news for him.
But after thinking carefully about it, I'm sure
it'll probably be tough for him to be rejected again.
Will Soma hear me out?
I don't know about that.
Yeah...
Thanks, Natsume! I'll give it a try.
See you later.
Okay.
You'll give it a try, huh?
I will, too.
We're gonna hold them off and turn the game around.
Yeah!
Mr. Gondo! I hurt my foot from that slide earlier.
Will you be okay?
Yes, sir! I'll be able to work tomorrow!
I don't mean tomorrow.
It'll be okay if you let Soma take the field.
Huh?
Take my place, Haruto!
It doesn't feel right using someone's glove.
Then, why don't you use this?
What?
This'll feel right.
Why do you have this?
You dropped it, so I picked it up.
Until the
last ball!
You're...
Seriously scary.
You should hurry up and take the field.
Everyone's waiting.
I'm counting on you, Haruto!
Well, I'll do my best if the ball comes my way.
There it goes! Right field!
Hey, don't actually come my way!
Dammit!
All right! Nice catch!
It's still four o'clock, you know.
We were so close today!
Just one more bat!
Yeah!
If we had one more bat, we—
Mr. Komada is Grand Slam Man, after all.
Meaning, it was definitely gonna be an easy out.
You asshole!
They're kinda different from my mom.
Hm?
Because she just works all the time.
My dad's like that, too.
Adults play ball and make a fuss about it, too, huh?
What is today's MVP doing in the corner?
The MVP is the pitcher of the opposing team who got
you out when you had the bases loaded, Mr. Komada.
Don't be ridiculous! Eat some noodles!
I'm already full.
You're still young! Eat more!
The game would've been all ours with that diving catch.
And if Soma got to bat, too.
Yeah, the noodles is really good here.
We've got a game next week, so come if you want.
See ya!
I'm the Grand Slam Man, dammit!
You know, I thought I wouldn't be able to
hang out like today, once I got a job.
Good thing you'll have a fun workplace.
Eita.
Hm?
Thanks for the glove.
It was nothing. I only picked it up.
Let's go home.
Oh, there's a place I need to stop by.
Diamond Building
Suizan University
Ah...
How—!
"How"?
Howdy.
Until the
last ball!
Oh?
You went to play baseball, huh?
My coworker invited me, so I couldn't turn down the offer.
How was it?
I didn't know what to think at first.
There were just old guys with beer bellies.
But they seriously tried to win the game.
I guess it was pretty fun.
Is that so? I'm glad to hear that.
Seems like you cheered up a bit.
Huh?
You were down in the dumps for about a week.
Not really... It was nothing.
But what about you?
What about me?
You always seem busy with work.
Are you worried about me?
I'm fine, though. Well, I suppose it's
hectic and, sometimes, very annoying.
But occasionally, there are good things about it.
Good things?
Like when my son carries my things for me.
Huh? What's that supposed to mean?
You'll understand once you become a parent.
What did you buy?
Nothing special.
What a creep.
It's just a manga.
I was just kidding.
You don't have to take it so personally.
Sorry.
It doesn't bother me.
Sorry about the other day, too.
I think I went too far when I told you
that it didn't involve you.
I was the one who said more than I should've. Sorry.
You didn't mean anything by it, right?
I guess.
So, why did you say that?
Stop requested.
What, aren't you getting off?
I am, but...
Never mind.
It isn't because you told me to,
but I thought I'd kind of make things clear to Soma.
I see.
The National Center Test is coming up, and I'd like
to focus on it. This isn't an excuse or anything.
I didn't think it was.
The other day, you told me it was.
I was pretty hurt.
If I'd been by your side at that time...
What did that mean? Did she realize or not?
January 7, Sunday
Hazuki
Do you have a bit of time tomorrow?
If I look back now,
I feel I might lose everything.
So yeah, I'm pretending not to look,
Keeping my lips closed tightly.
If I'd been by your side at that time,
I wonder what I would have said.
Hey, what will your answer be?
I want to stay like this, not knowing anything,
With this same distance between us.
Just a bit clumsy... just a bit grown-up...
This incomplete emotion is "pain".
What was your answer, ruler of my heart?
I want to know. I don't want to know. I want to know...